Guide to the Elizabeth Robins Papers 1851-1942
Washington State University Libraries Manuscripts, Archives, and Special Collections
Elizabeth Robins Papers
1851-1942
Washington State University Libraries, Manuscripts, Archives, and Special Collections Pullman, WA 99164-5610 USA (509) 335-6691 http://www.wsulibs.wsu.edu/masc/ mascref@wsu.edu
Cage 8
Robins, Elizabeth
1 containers. .25 linear feet of shelf space.
Letters received from John Galsworthy, Somerset Maugham, William Archer, Charles Trevelyan, Isabelle Smith, George M. Trevelyan, and others. Notes and notebook of Norwegian-English translating vocabulary.
Robins, Elizabeth. (married name: Mrs. George Richmond Parks; pseud. C.E. Raimond) ca. 1865-1952. American actress and author. Played principally in Ibsen.
Wrote: Below the salt (1896) The open question (1898) The magnetic north (1904) A dark lantern (1905) Come and find me (1908) The mills of the Gods (1908) and others. Also suffragist works. [New Century Cyclopedia of Names]
Correspondence with John Galsworthy, Somerset Maugham, William Archer, Charles P. Trevelyan, Isabelle Smith, George Macaulay Trevelyan, and others. Principally regarding Portrait of a lady, after 1940.
This collection is open for research use.
This collection is indexed under the following headings in the online catalog. Researchers desiring materials about related topics, persons, or places should search the catalog using these headings.
Robins, Elizabeth, 1862-1952--Archives; Smith, Isabelle; Archer, William, 1856-1924; Galsworthy, John, 1867-1933; Maugham, W. Somerset (William Somerset), 1874-1965; Trevelyan, Charles Philips, Sir, 1870-1958; Trevelyan, George Macaulay, 1876-1962
Actors--England--Correspondence; Authors--England--Correspondence; Translators--England--Correspondence
Literature
The following section contains a detailed listing of the materials in the collection.
- Reveille, devoted to the disabled sailor and soldier, no. 1. London. John Galsworthy, editor., August, 1918; 1 item. (Folder 1)
  - Enclosed: John Galsworthy, letter, Devon, to Elizabeth Robins, asking her to write a contribution., August 19, 1918; 1 l. holograph signed. (Folder 1)
  - Enclosed: Photograph of Elizabeth Robins., undated; 1 item. (Folder 1)
- Undated Papers
  - Sybil and B., letter, Sunday, Tithe Farm, Stoke Poges, Bucks, no addressee., undated; 1 l. holograph signed. (Folder 2)
  - Note: 'Gertrude Bell,' vol. 11, p. 512, 615., undated; 1 l. ms. (Folder 2)
  - Maugham, W.S., letter, New York, to Miss Robins., undated; 2 l. holograph signed. (Folder 2)
  - [Olhim?], Dorothy, letter, Brighton, to Dr. Wilberforce., undated; 1 l. holograph signed. (Folder 2)
  - Gordon, Laura, letter, [Hempstead?], to Octavia, December 5, n.y.; 2 l. holograph signed. (Folder 2)
  - Carter, Alice, letter, Nassau, to Miss Robins, January 27, n.y.; 2 l. holograph signed. (Folder 2)
  - Archer, William, letter, Monday, London, to Miss Robins, [1893]; 2 l. holograph signed. (Folder 2)
- Dated Papers
  - Bowen, M., letter, Zanesville, [Ohio], to Sallie E. Robins, n.p., April 2, [18]51; 2 l. holograph signed, with envelope. (Folder 3)
  - [Bull, Sara C.], letter, Cambridge, Mass., to Elizabeth Robins, Milwaukee, Wis., September 25, [1818]; 1 l. holograph signed. (Folder 3)
  - Dupont, Aime. Photograph of Francis Wilson, holograph inscription, to Elizabeth Robins., 1900; 1 item. (Folder 3)
  - [Milner, Edith?], letter, York, to Elizabeth Robins, September 9, 1905; 2 l. holograph signed. (Folder 3)
  - Trevelyan, Charles, letter, Westminster, to Lisa, [Bath], March 24, 1921; 1 l. holograph signed. (Folder 3)
  - Note: part of a letter., December, 1926; 1 l. typescript & ms. (Folder 3)
  - Note and telegraph envelope., September 10, 1927; 2 items. (Folder 3)
  - Wood, Fred F., letter, Sussex, to Dr. Wilberforce, April 28, 1933; 1 l. folded, holograph signed. (Folder 4)
  - Moore, Tom Sturge, letter, The Shiffolds, to Dear Ladies, March 12, 1940; 1 l. holograph signed. (Folder 4)
  - Note, on letterhead: Valour House, Fernand's Point, Southwest Harbor, Maine; enclosing clipping: 'The Yates-Thompson Sale,' Times Literary Supplement, April 10, 1941.; 3 l. (Folder 4)
  - Smith, Isabelle, letter, Ching, to Octavia., July 15, [1941]?; 1 l. holograph signed. (Folder 4)
  - Chancellor, Elsie, letter, Henley-on-Thames, to Elizabeth Robins, Valour House, Southwest Harbor, Maine, July 22, [1941]; 2 l.holograph signed, with envelope. (Folder 4)
  - Smith, Isabelle, letter, [London], to Miss Robins, n.p., July 27, 1941; 1 l. holograph signed. (Folder 5)
  - Letter, [date on envelope], London, to Miss Robins, New York. [Signature illegible], May 5, 1941; 2 l. holograph signed, with envelope. (Folder 5)
  - Smith, Isabelle, letter, London, to Octavia., August 12, 1941; 1 l. holograph signed. (Folder 5)
  - Trevelyan, G(eorge] M[acaulay], letter, Trinity College, Cambridge, to Miss Robins, n.p., August 15, 1941; 1 l. holograph signed. (Folder 5)
  - Jones, Thomas, letter, Harlech, to Miss Robins, Somesville, Maine., August 20, 1941; 1 l. holograph signed. (Folder 5)
  - Letter, Surrey, to "My Dear", initialed, in envelope addressed to Elizabeth Robins, Mount Desert, Maine, post-marked September 11,1941., April 27, 1941; 2 l. holograph (Folder 5)
  - Draper, Martha, letter, New York, to Miss Robins, n.p., signed, with pencilled draft of reply., October 8, 1941; 1 l. typescript (Folder 5)
  - Envelope, torn, postmarked., April 2, 1942.; 1 item. (Folder 5)
  - Translating vocabulary for Ibsen plays, Norwegian-English., August, 1892; 1 volume (Folder 6)
  - Loose notes and papers re: translation, 1895-1896; 34 l. (Folder 6)
- Letters found in Elizabeth Robins' books:
  - L.A. Maidstone, letter, Herstmonceux Place, Hailsham, to Miss Robins., June 30, n.y.; 2 l. holograph signed. (Folder 7)
  - L.A. Maidstone, letter, Herstmonceux Place, Hailsham, to Miss Robins. In: Aeschylus, The house of Atreus. Trans. by E.D.A. Morshead. London, Simpkin & Marshall; Winchester, Warren & Son, n.d., July 5, n.y.; 4 l. holograph signed. (Folder 7)
  - [Lucy Lane Clifford], letter, [London], to Lisa, signed: L. In: Mrs. W.K. [Lucy Lane] Clifford, Sir George's objection. London, Thomas Nelson, 1901., November 11, n.y.; 1 l. holograph. (Folder 7)
  - Mary A. Ward, letter, [London], to Miss Robins. In: Mary A. Ward, Eleanor: a play in four acts. London, Smith Elder, 1901., October 10, 1902; 1 l. holograph signed. (Folder 7)
  - [Florence Bell], letter, Redcar, to [Elizabeth Robins?] In: William Shakespeare, The Tempest. London, J.M. Dent, 1903. [Inscribed: To Elizabeth Robins from F.B.], September 28, 1904; 2 l. typescript. (Folder 7)
  - Bond, telegram, Hempstead C[ourt], to Miss Robins, Kensington. In: Elizabeth Robins [C.E. Raimond], A dark Lantern. London and New York, Macmillan, 1905., June 5, 1905; 1 l. with envelope. (Folder 7)
  - Robert W. Chambers, letter, [New York], to Miss Robbins. In: Elizabeth Robins [C.E. Raimond], Come and find me. London, William Heinemann. 1908., March 18, 1908; 1 l. holograph signed. (Folder 7)
  - Maggie Ponsonby, letter, [London], to Miss Robins, In: Magdalen Ponsonby, Idle women - a study in futility. London, Arthur L. Humphreys, 1914., 1 l. holograph signed. (Folder 7)
  - Emily M. Ritchie, letter, Sussex, to Miss Robins. In: Emily Marion Ritchie, Edith Sichel: Letters, verses, and other writings. Printed for private circulation, 1918., August 22, [1918?]; 1 l. holograph signed. (Folder 7)
  - [Frank von Kitlitz?], letter, Wehrkirch Land, Germany, to Octavia. In: Thomas de Quincy, Confessions of an English opium eater. London, George Routledge, 1886., November 20, 1937; 2 l. holograph signed. (Folder 7)
- Article found in Reveille:
  - Mortimer, Raymond, "Published at Last: An Adventure of 1900." A critique of Elizabeth Robins book Raymond and I., undated; 1 item. (Folder 8)